algomau.ca 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy - Algoma

###### Access to Information

A request for information contained in our records may be made formally under the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act.  However, it is not always necessary to file an official request as Algoma University provides information to the public through a number of its academic and administrative units. Informal inquiries are welcomed.

Formal requests for access to information are made under the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act.  This request must be in writing, accompanied by a $5 application fee, and provide enough detail to allow the University to identify the records.  All requests must also include contact information including name, address, and day-time telephone number.

To begin the process, you may contact us by emailing [FIPPA@algomau.ca](mailto:FIPPA@algomau.ca).

For more information and details on the request procedure, please read through our [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Policy](https://my.algomau.ca/tools/documents/policies/Privacy/FIPPA.pdf) (PDF).

###### Protection of Privacy

Algoma University takes the protection of the personal information seriously, and aims to collect only the specific personal information that is needed for the operation of the University.

Personal information will be used, maintained, disclosed, and disposed of in accordance with the applicable provincial or federal legislation.

If you have a concern or questions about the protection of your personal information, please contact us by emailing [privacy@algomau.ca](mailto:privacy@algomau.ca).
